I want to tell you three stories
我想给大家讲三个故事，
about the power of relationships
是关于用人际关系的力量
to solve the deep and complex social problems of this century.
去解决本世纪深刻和复杂的社会问题。
You know, sometimes it seems like all these problems
有时候，似乎所有的问题
of poverty, inequality, ill health, unemployment, violence, addiction --
比如贫穷、不平等、疾病、 失业、暴力、吸毒等等，
they're right there in one person's life.
恰好都发生在同一个人身上。
So I want to tell you about someone like this that I know.
我认识的一个人正是如此。
I'm going to call her Ella.
她叫艾拉。
Ella lives in a British city on a run down estate.
艾拉住在英国某处，一个破败的小区里。
The shops are closed, the pub's gone,
那里商店关门，酒吧歇业，
the playground's pretty desolate and never used,
游乐场日渐荒芜，无人问津，
and inside Ella's house, the tension is palpable
艾拉家中也成天气氛紧张，
and the noise levels are deafening.
吵闹不堪。
The TV's on at full volume.
电视声音总是调到最大。
One of her sons is fighting with one of her daughters.
她的一个儿子跟一个女儿在打架。
Another son, Ryan, is keeping up this constant stream of abuse from the kitchen,
另一个儿子，瑞恩， 不停地在厨房骂骂咧咧，
and the dogs are locked behind the bedroom door and straining.
狗被关在卧室里，不停地挣扎。
Ella is stuck.
艾拉仿佛深陷泥潭。
She has lived with crisis for 40 years.
她已经这样生活了40年。
She knows nothing else, and she knows no way out.
她对外界一无所知，也找不到出路。
She's had a whole series of abusive partners,
她之前的每一个伴侣都虐待她，
and, tragically, one of her children has been taken into care by social services.
可悲的是，其中一个孩子还被福利院带走了。
The three children that still live with her
仍跟她生活在一起的三个孩子
suffer from a whole range of problems, and none of them are in education.
都没有上学，身上问题多多。
And Ella says to me that she is repeating the cycle
艾拉跟我说，她的人生是
of her own mother's life before her.
在重蹈她母亲的覆辙。
But when I met Ella, there were 73 different services
然而当我遇见艾拉的时候， 她和家人生活的城市
on offer for her and her family in the city where she lives,
有73家不同的社会福利机构 可以为他们提供帮助。
73 different services run out of 24 departments in one city,
这73家福利机构 分属该市24个不同的部门，
and Ella and her partners and her children were known to most of them.
而大多数部门对艾拉一家 的情况非常了解。
They think nothing of calling social services
而他们一家从未想过要找这些部门，
to try and mediate one of the many arguments that broke out.
来调解他们家庭的矛盾。
And the family home was visited on a regular basis by social workers,
其实有很多人会定期到她家走访，比如社工，
youth workers, a health officer, a housing officer, a home tutor
青少年社工，卫生官员， 房屋事务官员，家庭教师
and the local policemen.
还有当地的警察。
And the governments say that there are 100,000 families
政府表示，目前在英国有10万个
in Britain today like Ella's,
像艾拉这样的家庭。
struggling to break the cycle of economic, social and environmental deprivation.
他们在贫困中挣扎，试图摆脱因经济、 社会和环境资源缺乏带来的恶性循环。
And they also say that managing this problem
政府还表示，为了解决上述问题，
costs a quarter of a million pounds per family per year
他们每年在每个家庭身上 要花费25万英镑，
and yet nothing changes.
然而毫无作用。
None of these well-meaning visitors are making a difference.
这些好心的家访者并没有发挥作用。
This is a chart we made in the same city with another family like Ella's.
这张图表显示的是我们为该市另外一个 类似艾拉家的家庭所做的事情。
This shows 30 years of intervention in that family's life.
它记录了30年来（福利机构） 对其家庭生活的干预。
And just as with Ella, not one of these interventions is part of an overall plan.
正如艾拉一样，这些干预都不成体系。
There's no end goal in sight.
缺乏明确的最终目标。
None of the interventions are dealing with the underlying issues.
没有着眼于解决根本问题。
These are just containment measures, ways of managing a problem.
只是一些应对措施，治标不治本。
One of the policemen says to me,
一位警官告诉我，
"Look, I just deliver the message and then I leave."
“我只是带个口信然后就走。”
So, I've spent time living with families like Ella's
因此，我去了很多不同的地方，
in different parts of the world,
跟像艾拉一样的家庭生活在一起。
because I want to know: what can we learn
因为我想搞清楚：在社会福利机构
from places where our social institutions just aren't working?
鞭长莫及的地方，到底发生了些什么？
I want to know what it feels like to live in Ella's family.
我想搞清楚，在艾拉家里 生活是一种什么感受。
I want to know what's going on and what we can do differently.
我想搞清楚，我们能做些什么来改变现状。
Well, the first thing I learned is that cost is a really slippery concept.
我弄明白的第一件事就是， “支出”是一个模糊的概念。
Because when the government says that a family like Ella's
因为当政府说，像艾拉这样的家庭，
costs a quarter of a million pounds a year to manage,
每年要花费政府25万英镑的时候，
what it really means
真正的含义是指，
is that this system costs a quarter of a million pounds a year.
维持福利系统运转， 每年需要花费25万英镑。
Because not one penny of this money actually touches Ella's family
而这些钱并没有用在艾拉身上，
in a way that makes a difference.
使她家的情况产生好转。
Instead, the system is just like this costly gyroscope
恰恰相反，福利体系就像一个昂贵的陀螺仪
that spins around the families, keeping them stuck at its heart,
不停地在这些家庭周围旋转， 把它们困在其中，
exactly where they are.
原地踏步。
And I also spent time with the frontline workers,
我还和一线社工交流过，
and I learned that it is an impossible situation.
我了解到这种情况根本无法好转。
So Tom, who is the social worker for Ella's 14-year-old son Ryan,
汤姆是一名社工，他负责 艾拉14岁的儿子瑞恩，
has to spend 86 percent of his time servicing the system:
他将自己86%的时间用于服务系统：
meetings with colleagues, filling out forms,
跟同事开会，填写表格，
more meetings with colleagues to discuss the forms,
继续跟同事开会研究怎么填写表格，
and maybe most shockingly,
而更让人震惊的是，
the 14 percent of the time he has to be with Ryan
剩下的14%的时间， 即使他与瑞恩在一块儿，
is spent getting data and information for the system.
也是在为系统获取数据和信息。
So he says to Ryan,
他问瑞恩，
"How often have you been smoking? Have you been drinking?
“你多久抽一次烟？ 你有喝酒吗？
When did you go to school?"
你什么时候去上学？”
And this kind of interaction rules out the possibility
在这种交流方式下，怎么可能
of a normal conversation.
进行正常的对话呢。
It rules out the possibility of what's needed
它完全抹杀了在汤姆和瑞恩之间
to build a relationship between Tom and Ryan.
建立正常的人际关系的可能性。
When we made this chart,
当我制作这张图表的时候，
the frontline workers, the professionals --
这些一线社工，专业人士们，
they stared at it absolutely amazed.
他们看着这张图表，大吃一惊。
It snaked around the walls of their offices.
数据曲线在他们办公室的墙上起起伏伏。
So many hours, so well meant, but ultimately so futile.
花费如此多的时间，怀揣如此美好的愿望，结果一事无成。
And there was this moment of absolute breakdown,
他们在这一刻彻底醒悟了，
and then of clarity:
他们清楚意识到：
we had to work in a different way.
必须要改变工作方式。
So in a really brave step, the leaders of the city where Ella lives
艾拉所在城市的领导者走出了勇敢的一步，
agreed that we could start by reversing Ryan's ratio.
同意我们将服务于系统的时间和 服务于瑞恩的时间比例调转。
So everyone who came into contact with Ella or a family like Ella's
于是每一位接触艾拉或类似家庭的社工，
would spend 80 percent of their time working with the families
必须用80%的时间服务于家庭，
and only 20 percent servicing the system.
剩下的20%时间服务于系统。
And even more radically,
更加重要的一点是，
the families would lead
家庭拥有决定权，
and they would decide who was in a best position to help them.
决定谁最有资格来帮助他们。
So Ella and another mother were asked to be part of an interview panel,
于是艾拉和另一位母亲加入了评审小组，
to choose from amongst the existing professionals
从现有的专业人士中挑选
who would work with them.
为自己服务的人。
And many, many people wanted to join us,
很多人想加入我们，
because you don't go into this kind of work to manage a system,
因为你不是为了维持系统 而加入这个工作，
you go in because you can and you want to make a difference.
而是因为你能也想为艾拉他们带来改变。
So Ella and the mother asked everybody who came through the door,
于是艾拉和这位母亲问 每一个参加评审的人，
"What will you do when my son starts kicking me?"
“如果你发现我儿子在踢打我，你会怎么办？”
And so the first person who comes in says,
第一个面试者说，
"Well, I'll look around for the nearest exit
“我会找到最近的一个出口，
and I will back out very slowly,
慢慢地退出去，
and if the noise is still going on, I'll call my supervisor."
如果事情还没有停止， 我会通知我的上司。”
And the mothers go, "You're the system. Get out of here!"
这位母亲说， “你只是在为体制工作。请你出去！”
And then the next person who comes is a policeman, and he says,
下一个进来的是一名警官，他说，
"Well, I'll tackle your son to the ground and then I'm not sure what I'll do."
“嗯，我会把你儿子摁倒在地， 但我不确定接下来我应该做什么。”
And the mothers say, "Thank you."
母亲说，“谢谢你。”
So, they chose professionals who confessed
于是，她们选择的是那些
they didn't necessarily have the answers,
可以坦诚自己未必有什么办法的人，
who said -- well, they weren't going to talk in jargon.
那些不会说套话的人。
They showed their human qualities and convinced the mothers
他们展现出的人性让这两位母亲相信，
that they would stick with them through thick and thin,
他们无论如何都会与自己同在，
even though they wouldn't be soft with them.
同时也不会过分纵容自己。
So these new teams and the families
尽管新的团队和家庭
were then given a sliver of the former budget,
只获得了之前预算的一小部分，
but they could spend the money in any way they chose.
但他们有权决定如何使用这笔钱。
And so one of the families went out for supper.
于是其中一家人选择出去吃晚饭。
They went to McDonald's and they sat down and they talked and they listened
他们去了麦当劳，围坐在一起， 谈天说地，
for the first time in a long time.
这是很久以来的第一次。
Another family asked the team
另一家人询问社工团队，
if they would help them do up their home.
能否帮他们修缮一下房子。
And one mother took the money
还有一位母亲用这钱
and she used it as a float to start a social enterprise.
作为备用金，开办了一家社企。
And in a really short space of time,
在短短时间内，
something new started to grow:
就出现了一些新气象：
a relationship between the team and the workers.
社工团队和家庭间建立了联系。
And then some remarkable changes took place.
之后又发生了一些显著的变化。
Maybe it's not surprising
也许艾拉在这个过程中，
that the journey for Ella has had some big steps backwards
经历了许多起起伏伏，
as well as forwards.
这一点也不奇怪。
But today, she's completed an IT training course,
但现在，她已经完成了IT训练课程，
she has her first paid job, her children are back in school,
找到了第一份工作， 孩子们也回到了学校，
and the neighbors,
而她的邻居们，
who previously just hoped this family would be moved anywhere
曾经希望她搬走，
except next door to them,
越远越好，
are fine.
现在关系也融洽了。
They've made some new friendships.
他们交到了新的朋友。
And all the same people have been involved in this transformation --
在这一变化中，人还是那些人，
same families, same workers.
同样的家庭，同样的社工，
But the relationship between them has been supported to change.
但他们之间的关系发生了变化。
So I'm telling you about Ella because I think that relationships
我之所以讲艾拉的故事， 是因为我认为人际关系
are the critical resource we have
是解决这类棘手问题
in solving some of these intractable problems.
最重要的资源。
But today, our relationships are all but written off
但现在，我们的人际关系， 已经被我们的政治，
by our politics, our social policies, our welfare institutions.
被我们的福利政策 和福利机构所破坏了。
And I've learned that this really has to change.
我意识到这必须发生改变。
So what do I mean by relationships?
到底什么是人际关系？
I'm talking about the simple human bonds between us,
我认为就是连接人与人的纽带，
a kind of authentic sense of connection, of belonging,
一种真实的联系感、归属感，
the bonds that make us happy, that support us to change,
它让我们感到开心，支持我们变得更好，
to be brave like Ella and try something new.
让我们像艾拉一样勇敢，尝试新的事物。
And, you know, it's no accident
知道吗，其实我并不意外，
that those who run and work in the institutions
那些福利机构的工作人员，
that are supposed to support Ella and her family
那些本应帮助艾拉 和她家人的工作人员，
don't talk about relationships,
从来不谈论人际关系，
because relationships are expressly designed out of a welfare model
因为人际关系从一开始 就没有被放进福利模式中，
that was drawn up in Britain and exported around the world.
而这一福利模式是在英国 出现并传遍世界的。
The contemporaries of William Beveridge,
威廉·贝弗里奇，
who was the architect of the first welfare state
是福利国度的设计者，
and the author of the Beveridge Report,
他撰写了《贝弗里奇报告》，
had little faith in what they called the average sensual or emotional man.
当时的人们不相信富有人情味的普通人，
Instead, they trusted this idea of the impersonal system
转而相信缺乏人情味的系统，
and the bureaucrat who would be detached and work in this system.
以及在系统中工作的官员们。
And the impact of Beveridge
贝弗里奇带来了巨大影响，
on the way the modern state sees social issues
他让人们看到，在一个现代国家中，
just can't be underestimated.
社会福利问题不容忽视。
The Beveridge Report sold over 100,000 copies
《贝弗里奇报告》在出版的最初几周，
in the first weeks of publication alone.
就售出了超过10万份。
People queued in the rain on a November night to get hold of a copy,
人们在11月的雨夜排队购买，
and it was read across the country, across the colonies, across Europe,
很快这份报告就传遍了全国， 传遍了殖民地，传遍了欧洲，
across the United States of America,
传遍了美国，
and it had this huge impact
它对福利模式在全球的形成
on the way that welfare states were designed around the globe.
产生了巨大的影响。
The cultures, the bureaucracies, the institutions -- they are global,
（福利）文化、体制、机构， 在全球得到推广，
and they've come to seem like common sense.
逐渐成为了一种普遍现象。
They've become so ingrained in us,
它们如此根深蒂固，
that actually we don't even see them anymore.
以至于我们开始对其熟视无睹。
And I think it's really important to say that in the 20th century,
我认为应该强调的是，在20世纪，
they were remarkably successful, these institutions.
这些福利机构的出现，是一种巨大的成功。
They led to longer lifespans, the eradication of mass disease,
（社会福利）延长了人们的寿命， 消除了大范围流行疾病
mass housing, almost universal education.
提供了住房，普及了教育。
But at the same time,
但与此同时，
Beveridge sowed the seeds of today's challenges.
贝弗里奇也埋下了今天种种问题的种子。
So let me tell you a second story.
接下来我要讲第二个故事。
What do you think today is a bigger killer than a lifetime of smoking?
你认为如今比终身吸烟 更加可怕的健康杀手是什么？
It's loneliness.
是孤独。
According to government statistics, one person over 60 -- one in three --
根据政府统计，60岁以上的人中， 有三分之一
doesn't speak to or see another person in a week.
在一周内不与人交流。
One person in 10, that's 850,000 people,
十分之一的人，也就是85万人，
doesn't speak to anyone else in a month.
甚至在一个月内不跟人交流。
And we're not the only people with this problem;
这种情况不仅发生在我们国家，
this problem touches the whole of the Western world.
在整个西方世界都是如此。
And it's even more acute in countries like China,
而在中国，形势更加严峻，
where a process of rapid urbanization, mass migration, has left older people
中国在经历迅速的城市化过程， 大量人口涌入城市，
alone in the villages.
村里只留下老人。
And so the services that Beveridge designed and exported --
而贝弗里奇设计和推广的福利体系，
they can't address this kind of problem.
根本无法预见这样的问题。
Loneliness is like a collective relational challenge,
孤独就像“人际关系危机综合症”，
and it can't be addressed by a traditional bureaucratic response.
靠传统的行政手段根本无法解决。
So some years ago, wanting to understand this problem,
于是几年前，为了研究这一问题，
I started to work with a group of about 60 older people
我在自己生活的伦敦城南， 与一群老年人共同生活，
in South London, where I live.
他们大约有60人。
I went shopping, I played bingo,
我跟他们一起购物，玩bingo游戏，
but mainly I was just observing and listening.
但大部分时间我只是观察和倾听。
I wanted to know what we could do differently.
我想知道我们该如何改变。
And if you ask them, people tell you they want two things.
如果你问他们有何需求，他们会提到两件事。
They want somebody to go up a ladder and change a light bulb,
他们希望有人能替他们爬梯子换灯泡，
or to be there when they come out of hospital.
或是从医院出来时有人接。
They want on-demand, practical support.
他们渴望实际的帮助。
And they want to have fun.
他们想过得快乐。
They want to go out, do interesting things with like-minded people,
他们想与志趣相投的人一起出门找乐子，
and make friends like we've all made friends at every stage of our lives.
想结交新的朋友，就像我们大家一样， 无论处在什么年龄。
So we rented a phone line, hired a couple of handymen,
于是我们开通了一条热线， 雇了一群能干的人，
and started a service we called "Circle."
（为老人家）提供服务，我们称之为“圈子”。
And Circle offers its local membership a toll-free 0 800 number
“圈子”为当地的会员开通了免费的0800电话，
that they can call on demand for any support.
他们可以随时打电话要求各种服务。
And people have called us for so many reasons.
他们打电话的原因各种各样。
They've called because their pets are unwell,
比如宠物生病了，
their DVD is broken, they've forgotten how to use their mobile phone,
DVD机坏了，或者忘记怎么用手机了，
or maybe they are coming out of hospital
或者从医院出来，
and they want someone to be there.
希望有人能接他们。
And Circle also offers a rich social calendar --
“圈子”还安排了丰富的社会活动，
knitting, darts, museum tours, hot air ballooning -- you name it.
学编织，玩飞镖，参观博物馆， 乘热气球，多种多样。
But here's the interesting thing, the really deep change:
但有意思的是，一个很大的变化产生了：
over time, the friendships that have formed
随着时间推移，他们之前形成了友谊，
have begun to replace the practical offer.
并且开始变得比那些实际的帮助更重要。
So let me tell you about Belinda.
下面我要讲讲关于贝琳达的事。
Belinda's a Circle member, and she was going into hospital for a hip operation,
贝琳达是“圈子”的会员， 她准备去医院做一个髋骨手术，
so she called her local Circle to say they wouldn't see her for a bit.
于是她给本地的“圈子”打了个电话， 说自己有一段时间不会参加活动。
And Damon, who runs the local Circle, calls her back and says, "How can I help?"
达蒙，是当地“圈子”的负责人， 他回电话问，“需要帮助吗？”
And Belinda says, "Oh no, I'm fine --
贝琳达说，“哦，不用了，我没事
Jocelyn is doing the shopping, Tony's doing the gardening,
乔斯琳帮我买东西，托尼帮我照顾花园，
Melissa and Joe are going to come in and cook and chat."
梅丽莎和乔会过来帮我做饭，陪我聊天。”
So five Circle members had organized themselves
五名“圈子”的成员分工合作，
to take care of Belinda.
照顾贝琳达。
And Belinda's 80, although she says that she feels 25 inside,
贝琳达今年80岁了， 尽管她说自己内心才25，
but she also says
她还说，
that she felt stuck and pretty down when she joined Circle.
初加入“圈子”的时候她感觉无助和低落。
But the simple act of encouraging her to come along to that first event
但社工们非常暖心地鼓励她 参加第一次活动时，
led to a process where natural friendships formed,
慢慢让他们成为了朋友，
friendships that today are replacing the need for expensive services.
跟昂贵的服务相比， 友谊成为了更重要的需求。
It's relationships that are making the difference.
正是人际关系带来了这一改变。
So I think that three factors have converged
因此我觉得，为什么我们如此重视人际关系
that enable us to put relationships at the heart and center
在解决社会问题中发挥的核心作用？
of how we solve social problems today.
原因有三点。
Firstly, the nature of the problems --
首先，社会问题的本质
they've changed, and they require different solutions.
发生了改变，因此需要不同的解决方式。
Secondly, the cost, human as much as financial, of doing business as usual.
其次是支出，就像做普通生意一样， 经费越多人手越多。
And thirdly, technology.
第三点就是科技。
I've talked about the first two factors.
前两个原因我刚才已经讲过了。
It's technology that enables these approaches to scale
正是科技扩大了我们的规模，
and potentially now support thousands of people.
让我们能服务数以千计的人。
So the technology we've used is really simple,
其实我们使用的技术非常简单，
it's made up of available things like databases, mobile phones.
无非就是数据库，手机这些有效的工具。
Circle has got this very simple system that underpins it,
“圈子”就是依靠一个简单的支持系统，
enables a small local team to support a membership of up to a thousand.
让一支小规模的本地团队 能服务多达一千名会员。
And you can contrast this with a neighborhood organization
大家可以将其与70年代的“邻里互助组织”
of the 1970s,
进行比较，
when this kind of scale just wasn't possible,
当时要做到如此大的规模根本不可能，
neither was the quality or the longevity that the spine of technology can provide.
服务质量和持续性 也远不如科技发达的今天。
So it's relationships underpinned by technology
因此，正是有了科技的支持
that can turn the Beveridge models on their heads.
贝弗里奇模式才能得以转变。
The Beveridge models are all about institutions with finite resources,
贝弗里奇模式中，福利机构的资源有限，
anonymously managing access.
并通过匿名方式进行管理。
In my work at the front line,
我在福利工作第一线的时候，
I've seen again and again how up to 80 percent of resource
不止一次见到高达80%的资源
is spent keeping people out.
用来将人们拒之门外。
So professionals have to administer
社工们不得不填写
these increasingly complex forms of administration
那些越来越复杂的管理表格
that are basically about stopping people accessing the service
得到的结果却是人们享受不到服务，
or managing the queue.
或者需要排很久的队。
And Circle, like the relational services that we and others have designed,
而“圈子”提供的，具有人情味的服务
inverts this logic.
扭转了局面。
What it says is, the more people, the more relationships,
有句话总结得好，参加的人越多， 人际关系越融洽，
the stronger the solution.
解决方案就越有效。
So I want to tell you my third and final story,
接下来是第三个也是最后一个故事，
which is about unemployment.
是关于失业的。
In Britain, as in most places in the world,
在英国，正如在其他国家一样，
our welfare states were primarily designed
福利机构的主要目标
to get people into work,
是帮助人们就业，
to educate them for this,
培训他们的职业技能，
and to keep them healthy.
保护他们的身体健康。
But here, too, the systems are failing.
然而同样的，这种体制并不成功。
And so the response has been
（政府采取的）措施是
to try and make these old systems even more efficient and transactional --
努力使旧体制变得更加有效和务实，
to speed up processing times, divide people into ever-smaller categories,
加快办理进程，将事务进行更细的分类，
try and target services at them more efficiently -- in other words,
尝试让服务更加精准和有效——换句话说，
the very opposite of relational.
让服务更加没有人情味。
But guess how most people find work today?
但你们知道现在大部分人如何找工作吗？
Through word of mouth.
口口相传。
It turns out that in Britain today, most new jobs are not advertised.
今天在英国，大部分新的工作 都不登招聘广告。
So it's friends that tell you about a job,
工作信息大都来自朋友，
it's friends that recommend you for a job,
朋友推荐给你一份工作，
and it's a rich and diverse social network that helps you find work.
丰富多样的社交圈子帮你找工作。
Maybe some of you here this evening are thinking,
也许今晚在场的有些人会想，
"But I found my job through an advert,"
“我就是通过招聘广告找到的工作呀。”
but if you think back, it was probably a friend that showed you the ad
但如果你回想一下， 也许是某一个朋友给你看了那条广告，
and then encouraged you to apply.
然后鼓励你去申请的。
But not surprisingly,
但毫不奇怪的是，
people who perhaps most need this rich and diverse network
那些最需要丰富人脉的人
are those who are most isolated from it.
恰恰是最离群索居的人。
So knowing this,
因此，明白了这一点，
and also knowing about the costs and failure of current systems,
也看到现有体制的高成本和低效率之后，
we designed something new with relationships at its heart.
我们以人际关系为核心设计出了新的服务方案。
We designed a service that encourages people to meet up,
我们推出了一项服务，鼓励人们见面，
people in and out of work,
无论是有工作的还是失业的，
to work together in structured ways
组织他们在一起工作，
and try new opportunities.
尝试新的机遇。
And, well, it's very hard to compare the results of these new systems
当然，很难将这一新模式的结果
with the old transactional models,
同旧的模式进行比较，
but it looks like, with our first 1,000 members,
但有一点值得注意， 在我们拥有了头1000个会员时，
we outperformed existing services by a factor of three,
我们在其中一项上就击败了现有的体制，
at a fraction of the cost.
就是花费变少了。
And here, too, we've used technology,
我们同样利用了现代科技，
but not to network people in the way that a social platform would do.
但并不是像一般的社交平台那种做法。
We've used it to bring people face to face and connect them with each other,
我们让人们面对面，彼此交流和建立联系，
building real relationships and supporting people to find work.
建立真正的人际关系，支持人们找到工作。
At the end of his life, in 1948,
1948年，在贝弗里奇去世前，
Beveridge wrote a third report.
他完成了第三份报告。
And in it he said he had made a dreadful mistake.
在报告里他坦承他犯了一个巨大的错误。
He had left people and their communities out.
他忽略了市民和社区的重要。
And this omission, he said, led to seeing people,
而这一疏漏，导致人们
and people starting to see themselves,
将别人，也将自己，
within the categories of the bureaucracies and the institutions.
归入政府部门和福利机构划分的人群类别中。
And human relationships were already withering.
人与人之间的关系被摧毁了。
But unfortunately, this third report was much less read
但不幸的是，跟贝弗里奇早期的作品相比，
than Beveridge's earlier work.
这第三份报告鲜有人问津。
But today, we need to bring people and their communities
但今天，在设计新的体制和服务过程中，
back into the heart of the way we design new systems and new services,
我们要将老百姓和他们的社区 放在核心位置来进行考虑，
in an approach that I call "Relational Welfare."
我称之为“暖心福利”。
We need to leave behind these old, transactional,
我们要抛弃那些陈旧的、交易性的、
unsuitable, outdated models,
不合适的、过时的模式，
and we need to adopt instead the shared collective relational responses
取而代之的，我们要采取 具有人情味的集体行动
that can support a family like Ella's,
来帮助像艾拉一样的家庭，
that can address an issue like loneliness,
来解决孤独问题，
that can support people into work and up the skills curve
来提高人们的专业技能，帮助他们
in a modern labor market,
在现代劳动市场上争得一席之地，
that can also address challenges of education, of health care systems,
来改善教育体制和医疗体系，
and so many more of those problems that are pressing on our societies.
还有其他一系列我们面临的 严峻的社会问题。
It is all about relationships.
人际关系是解决问题的关键。
Relationships are the critical resource we have.
人际关系是我们最重要的资源。
Thank you.
谢谢大家。
(Applause)
（掌声）